<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on asenchi.com</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on asenchi.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Curt Micol &lt;asenchi@asenchi.com&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 10:30:51 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Consulting</title>
      <link>/posts/consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 10:30:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/consulting/</guid>
      <description>This week I posted on LinkedIn and Twitter that I was making myself available to consult with companies on their infrastructure. I thought I might dive into why I am doing this.
Starting a Business Starting a business is hard, especially when considering building software. Open source is predominant (rightfully so) and Software as a Service (SaaS) is the trend. I have spent the past couple of months working through a business plan and have some pretty ambitious goals.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This week I posted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/curt-micol-852472178_in-addition-to-the-work-i-am-doing-at-infrastellar-activity-6982748228479844353-Pteh?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/asenchi/status/1576983616315445249&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that I was
making myself available to consult with companies on their infrastructure. I
thought I might dive into why I am doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-a-business&#34;&gt;Starting a Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting a business is hard, especially when considering building
software. Open source is predominant (rightfully so) and Software as a Service
(SaaS) is the trend. I have spent the past couple of months working through a
business plan and have some pretty ambitious goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a plan is all well and good, and I started diving in right away. However
I realized two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My life outside of work has been incredibly busy and required more attention
than I was willing to acknowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My experience in the tech industry has been comprised of bleeding edge tech
startups that represent a small portion of the practices around
infrastructure and incident management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first point is just a matter of timelines lining up. With a family and
responsibilities there isn&amp;rsquo;t much I can do here. It is a reality that I have to
live with that my time right now comes at a higher cost. Everything is fine and
our family is flourishing, and part of that is because I prioritize that work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also found that when working alone it easy to make that excuse. The
flexibility itself needs to be constrained and while I am working on that it
means I have to find a practical way forward to be able to sustain my work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second point was something I have thought about for a while. I have a few
products that I am working on that would benefit from a more varied perspective
than the startups I have worked for. It is true I worked at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tanzu.vmware.com&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;, which is
anything but a startup, however, the business unit I was in was very
similar. We were quite isolated from the rest of the company and had autonomy
to make the decisions we needed to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of companies out there that have production systems that are a
vastly different shape than some of those I have worked on. I want to build
products that help them. I also want to understand where the pain is that they
are experiencing. It would be easy for me to build something I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; is
right, but it means much more to users to build something that &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt; for
them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the cross section of these two areas I think it is good time to open up
my time to others. Not only does this provide me some income while I do this
research but it also gives me a more clearly defined schedule while I work on
getting organized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty excited about the prospect. I have learned over the years
that I only see in part and working with others produces something much more
fulfilling. I want to help companies develop empathetic incident management
systems, build and managed infrastructure that doesn&amp;rsquo;t immediately become a
heaping pile of technical debt, and help companies grow their infrastructure
while being easy to maintain and adapt to their business needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a proven track record of reliable, pragmatic solutions when it comes to
infrastructure, incident management, and team building. I think I can help your
company improve in some of these areas. If you have a problem that you need
help on, reach out to me at
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:asenchi@infrastellar.systems&#34;&gt;asenchi@infrastellar.systems&lt;/a&gt; and let&amp;rsquo;s
chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to working with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honoring Dr Richard I. Cook</title>
      <link>/posts/honoring-dr-cook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 14:07:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/honoring-dr-cook/</guid>
      <description>Today I learned of the passing of Dr. Richard I. Cook. As I mentioned in my previous post he is the author of &amp;ldquo;How Complex Systems Fail&amp;rdquo; which is, I believe, one of the most important documents on complex systems ever written. If you run any type of system that is in production or is relied upon by people in a significant way, this document should be studied and well understood.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Today I &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lund_hfss/status/1568242140546744322&#34;&gt;learned of the passing of Dr. Richard I. Cook&lt;/a&gt;. As I mentioned in my
previous post he is the author of &amp;ldquo;How Complex Systems Fail&amp;rdquo; which is, I
believe, one of the most important documents on complex systems ever
written. If you run any type of system that is in production or is relied upon
by people in a significant way, this document should be studied and well
understood. It is a seminal work, one that I have read quarterly for the past
8-10 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never know what to say about people passing, but I want to thank Dr. Cook for
his work and influence. I owe a great deal of my career to him and his work. He
forced me to view systems in a completely different way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2S0k12uZR14&#34;&gt;brilliant talk he gave at Velocity 2012&lt;/a&gt;. You should also
check out his book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.routledge.com/Behind-Human-Error-2nd-Edition/Woods-Dekker-Cook-Johannesen-Sarter/p/book/9780754678342&#34;&gt;Behind Human Error&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My prayers are with his family and friends during this difficult time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with Catastrophe</title>
      <link>/posts/dealing-with-catastrophe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 15:58:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dealing-with-catastrophe/</guid>
      <description>6 Catastrophe is always just around the corner.
Complex systems possess potential for catastrophic failure. Human practitioners are nearly always in close physical and temporal proximity to these potential failures – disaster can occur at any time and in nearly any place. The potential for catastrophic outcome is a hallmark of complex systems. It is impossible to eliminate the potential for such catastrophic failure; the potential for such failure is always present by the system’s own nature.</description>
      <content>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 Catastrophe is always just around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complex systems possess potential for catastrophic failure. Human
practitioners are nearly always in close physical and temporal proximity to
these potential failures – disaster can occur at any time and in nearly any
place. The potential for catastrophic outcome is a hallmark of complex
systems. It is impossible to eliminate the potential for such catastrophic
failure; the potential for such failure is always present by the system’s own
nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above quote is taken from Dr. Richard Cook&amp;rsquo;s seminal treatise, &lt;a href=&#34;https://how.complexsystems.fail&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;How Complex
Systems Fail&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. The full paper is a must read for anyone working on
infrastructure and complex systems. However, this sixth point is of particular
importance to me because it has become a fundamental approach to every system I
have worked on since reading Dr. Cook&amp;rsquo;s paper nearly 12 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience has shown this statement to be true. No matter how hard teams
worked to build reliable systems there was always an event that surprised us,
one that typically meant many people were going to lose many hours of their day
working to resolve the underlying incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximately eight years ago I joined a new company that was in the middle of
a very large migration. The work had been in progress for 18 months. Even with all of that
preparation we still experienced a catastrophic event that impacted a large
portion of our customers for greater than 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most surprising piece at the time was that our planning didn&amp;rsquo;t just
fall apart from a technical perspective, but we also saw results of a massive
communication breakdown that led to the confusion of our coworkers and our
customers. We had done the work to put together checklists with specific points
of communication to ensure we were all on the same page. We had assigned the
Incident Commander role to a rotation of people who understood the work and
they did a reasonable job updating situation reports. Yet when we finished the
internal post-mortem and shared it with our coworkers, many of them were
shocked to find out what had happened. There was an obvious problem here, one
that we had thought we had prepared for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, the Director of our operations team at the time understood the
importance of finding a better way to deal with failure and gave me the space
to develop a method for our needs. I was deeply curious to find a better way
to engage our systems and support the teams across the company so that whenever
we faced a failure, whether planned or unplanned, my coworkers had the
information they needed to continue doing their job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time three key areas stuck out to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The burden of response: How can the process of incident response reduce the
stress on those actively addressing the incident?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear and concise communication: How to inform all impacted parties whether
known or not?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-technical Allies: How can the process of incident response support all
teams at all levels in the company that may be impacted by the particulars of
incident?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any system that could solve these three issues would greatly improve our
ability to address not only catastrophic failures but any incident encountered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work we are doing at &lt;a href=&#34;https://infrastellar.systems&#34;&gt;Infrastellar Systems&lt;/a&gt; is an extension of that
initial development of an incident management system. It is one that I have
continued to develop throughout the years. I&amp;rsquo;ve built up a lot of experience
integrating my system into large organizations. What I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from those
experiences I hope to put into tooling for companies to improve their
experience around catastrophic failures and more deeply understand their
production systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the potential for failure exists in every system we develop. As
Dr. Cook says above, it is &amp;ldquo;always present by the system&amp;rsquo;s own nature.&amp;rdquo;
Incident management is an interface by which companies engage with their
systems in real-time. It isn&amp;rsquo;t the only one, but it may just be the most
important one.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Sustainable Business</title>
      <link>/posts/building-a-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 13:26:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/building-a-business/</guid>
      <description>Recently I posted on LinkedIn that I am starting a new adventure as a business owner and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more excited about this opportunity. The company is called Infrastellar Systems and we will be focused on building tools and processes for running small to large infrastructure systems in a reliable fashion.
Running a company has been a dream of mine for some time and I want to build a sustainable, value-driven company; one that treasures the valuable resources of this world and doesn&amp;rsquo;t squander them for meaningless riches for a select few.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Recently I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:ugcPost:6960249439840043009?utm_source=linkedin_share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop_share&amp;amp;utm_content=post&#34;&gt;posted on LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; that I am starting a new
adventure as a business owner and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more excited about this
opportunity. The company is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://infrastellar.systems&#34;&gt;Infrastellar Systems&lt;/a&gt; and we
will be focused on building tools and processes for running small to large
infrastructure systems in a reliable fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a company has been a dream of mine for some time and I want to build a
sustainable, value-driven company; one that treasures the valuable resources of
this world and doesn&amp;rsquo;t squander them for meaningless riches for a select few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infrastellar Systems aims to be a one-hundred year infrastructure company. What
that means exactly we&amp;rsquo;re still figuring out, but the company needs to be
sustainable and responsive to changes in tech, society, and economies. It needs
to be one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t lock people in to ensure we acquire the next buck but
build value into the people who use our tools so that they can make the
decisions that benefit their business. Honestly it seems absurdly difficult to
build a business given the state of the world at the moment, but I&amp;rsquo;m excited to
try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to share more details on how I am approaching this adventure here on
this site and &lt;a href=&#34;https://infrastellar.systems&#34;&gt;Infrastellar Systems&lt;/a&gt;. I invite you to join me for
this adventure. I am also very interested in &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:asenchi@asenchi.com&#34;&gt;hearing from
you&lt;/a&gt; about what you think is required for a business
to succeed in today&amp;rsquo;s environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
