<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on asenchi.com</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on asenchi.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Curt Micol &lt;asenchi@asenchi.com&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 14:07:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Honoring Dr Richard I. Cook</title>
      <link>/posts/honoring-dr-cook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 14:07:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/honoring-dr-cook/</guid>
      <description>Today I learned of the passing of Dr. Richard I. Cook. As I mentioned in my previous post he is the author of &amp;ldquo;How Complex Systems Fail&amp;rdquo; which is, I believe, one of the most important documents on complex systems ever written. If you run any type of system that is in production or is relied upon by people in a significant way, this document should be studied and well understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with Catastrophe</title>
      <link>/posts/dealing-with-catastrophe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 15:58:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dealing-with-catastrophe/</guid>
      <description>6 Catastrophe is always just around the corner.
Complex systems possess potential for catastrophic failure. Human practitioners are nearly always in close physical and temporal proximity to these potential failures – disaster can occur at any time and in nearly any place. The potential for catastrophic outcome is a hallmark of complex systems. It is impossible to eliminate the potential for such catastrophic failure; the potential for such failure is always present by the system’s own nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Sustainable Business</title>
      <link>/posts/building-a-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 13:26:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/building-a-business/</guid>
      <description>Recently I posted on LinkedIn that I am starting a new adventure as a business owner and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more excited about this opportunity. The company is called Infrastellar Systems and we will be focused on building tools and processes for running small to large infrastructure systems in a reliable fashion.
Running a company has been a dream of mine for some time and I want to build a sustainable, value-driven company; one that treasures the valuable resources of this world and doesn&amp;rsquo;t squander them for meaningless riches for a select few.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
