<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>asenchi.com</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on asenchi.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Curt Micol &lt;asenchi@asenchi.com&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 10:57:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>About me I&amp;rsquo;m an infrastructure engineer. I live near Lansing, MI. I am particularly interested in Resilience Engineering when applied to complex infrastructure systems. I&amp;rsquo;ve been blessed to work on some relatively large platforms including EngineYard, Heroku, GitHub, Simple, and VMware Tanzu.
I am also interested in the intersection of complex systems and humans in the area of incident management. I have developed a system called the Incident Complexity Framework and am working on a book and training course for helping companies apply incident management practices.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an infrastructure engineer. I live near Lansing, MI. I am particularly
interested in &lt;a href=&#34;https://erikhollnagel.com/ideas/resilience-engineering.html&#34;&gt;Resilience Engineering&lt;/a&gt; when applied to
complex infrastructure systems. I&amp;rsquo;ve been blessed to work on some relatively
large platforms including &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineyard.com&#34;&gt;EngineYard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://heroku.com&#34;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://simple.com&#34;&gt;Simple&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://tanzu.vmware.com/&#34;&gt;VMware
Tanzu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also interested in the intersection of complex systems and humans in the
area of incident management. I have developed a system called the Incident
Complexity Framework and am working on a book and training course for helping
companies apply incident management practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of computers I imagine a world where technology is used to benefit
people and not consume the world in greed. Unfortunately we are a long way from
this happening. Ultimately, I think software should compliment human driven
progress and not overwhelm it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
