<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>infrastructure on asenchi.com</title>
    <link>/tags/infrastructure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in infrastructure on asenchi.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Curt Micol &lt;asenchi@asenchi.com&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 10:30:51 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Consulting</title>
      <link>/posts/consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 10:30:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/consulting/</guid>
      <description>This week I posted on LinkedIn and Twitter that I was looking to work with companies on their infrastructure. I thought I might dive into why I am doing this.
Starting a Business Starting a business is hard, especially when considering building software. Open source is predominant (rightfully so) and Software as a Service (SaaS) is the trend. I have spent the past couple of months working through a business plan and have some pretty ambitious goals.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This week I posted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/curt-micol-852472178_in-addition-to-the-work-i-am-doing-at-infrastellar-activity-6982748228479844353-Pteh?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/asenchi/status/1576983616315445249&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that I was looking to work with
companies on their infrastructure. I thought I might dive into why I am doing
this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-a-business&#34;&gt;Starting a Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting a business is hard, especially when considering building
software. Open source is predominant (rightfully so) and Software as a Service
(SaaS) is the trend. I have spent the past couple of months working through a
business plan and have some pretty ambitious goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a plan is all well and good, and I started diving in right away. However
I realized two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My life outside of work has been incredibly busy and required more attention
than I was willing to recognize.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My experience in the tech industry has been comprised of bleeding edge tech
startups that represent a small portion of the practices around
infrastructure and incident management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first point is just a matter of timelines lining up. With a family and
responsibilities there isn&amp;rsquo;t much I can do here. It is a reality that I have to
live with that my time right now comes at a higher cost. Everything is fine and
our family is flourishing, and part of that is because I prioritize that work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also found that when working alone it easy to make that excuse. The
flexibility itself needs to be constrained and while I am working on that it
means I have to find a practical way forward to be able to sustain my work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second point was something I have thought about for a while. I have a few
products that I am working on that would benefit from a more varied perspective
than the startups I have worked for. It is true I worked at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tanzu.vmware.com&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;, which is
anything but a startup, however, the business unit I was in was very
similar. We were quite isolated from the rest of the company and had autonomy
to make the decisions we needed to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of companies out there that have production systems that are a
vastly different shape than some of those I have worked on. I want to build
products that help them. I also want to understand where the pain is that they
are experiencing. It would be easy for me to build something I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; is
right, but it means much more to users to build something that &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt; for
them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the cross section of these two areas I think it is good time to open up
my time to others. Not only does this provide me some income while I do this
research but it also gives me a more clearly defined schedule while I work on
getting organized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty excited about the prospect. I have learned over the years
that I only see in part and working with others produces something much more
fulfilling. I want to help companies develop empathetic incident management
systems, build and managed infrastructure that doesn&amp;rsquo;t immediately become a
heaping pile of technical debt, and help companies grow their infrastructure
while being easy to maintain and adapt to their business needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a proven track record of reliable, pragmatic solutions when it comes to
infrastructure, incident management, and team building. I think I can help your
company improve in some of these areas. If you have a problem that you need
help on, reach out to me at
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:asenchi@infrastellar.systems&#34;&gt;asenchi@infrastellar.systems&lt;/a&gt; and let&amp;rsquo;s
chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to working with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
